Jack: So, what exactly is a project
manager and what do they do?
Project management has always been
important in business and is getting
more so all the time as project
management skills are in more demand.
Project managers are responsible
for overseeing all the processes
we have just looked at, Initiating,
planning, executing, monitoring,
and controlling and closing.
These are also known as
the ‘project life cycle’.
They don’t do this on their own but
instead are involved in all the different
stages in one capacity or another and
they may not even be assigned to the
role until the project is underway.
It is their responsibility to make
sure that the right people are
assigned to the right roles and that
all planning is carried out properly
to achieve the target outcome.
They will also protect the team
from any distractions and lead them
through the executing of the project.
They will also be on top of monitoring
the progress of the project at all stages
and addressing any issues that may arise.
At closing they will be responsible
for making sure everything has been
finalised and working with the client
or stakeholders to get everything
signed off and reviewing the process.
Let’s hear what it is like
to be a project manager.